咸宁市二零二零年初中毕业生学业考试。一情景交际。听下面五个提示句，从每小题三个选项中选出能回应提示句的最佳选项。听每个提示句前，你将有时间阅读各个小题，每小题五秒钟。听完后，各个小题将给出。读五秒钟的作答时间，每个提示句读两遍。
May I ask you some questions about Chang 4?
二听对话，选图。听下面五段对话，每段对话后有一个问题。从下面所给的六个图片选项中，选出相应问题的最佳选项。其中有一个为干扰选项。听。读完每段对话后，你将有五秒钟的作答时间。每段对话读两遍。
we do to reduce the pollution?
Pollution has caused too many problems.
Yes, we should plant more trees to reduce the pollution.
Question What can we do to reduce the pollution?
Text 7 Could you give me some advice on how to learn English well?
Sure. I think reading a good English newspaper is helpful.
Question What's the girl's advice about learning English?
Could you give me some advice on how to learn English well?
Sure. I think reading a good English newspaper is helpful.
What's the girl's advice about learning English?
Text 8 I went to the zoo with my parents yesterday.
The panda is so cute.
I like it much.
But I like the elephant more.
Which animal does the boy like?
I went to the zoo with my parents yesterday.
The panda is so cute.
I like it much.
But I like the elephant more.
Which animal does the boy like?
Text 9 What kind of home do you live in?
It's a townhouse with two floors.
Question What kind of home does the boy live in?
What kind of home do you live in?
It's a townhouse with two floors.
Question What kind of home does the boy live in?
It's townhouse Text 10
When is the International Tea Day?
Do you know?
Well, it's on May 21st, and China is the home of tea.
Question What are they talking about?
Text When is the International Tea Day?
Do you know?
Well, it's on May 21st, and China is the home of tea.
Question What are they talking about?
三对话理解。听下面三段对话，从每小题三个选项中选出相应问题的最佳选项。听每段对话前，你将有时间阅读各个小题。每。小题五秒钟。听完后，各个小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。每段对话读两遍，听下面一段对话，回答十一至十三小题。
What are they talking Text 12 What are talking about?
Text 11 What me see your pictures.
Who's this? This is my father.
He's a teacher.
What does he often do in his spare time?
He often goes fishing.
And is this your mother?
She looks beautiful.
Yeah, she likes reading.
She goes to the library three times a week.
I see. And this?
Oh, that's my brother.
He is an engineer.
Great. You have a happy family.
Let me see your pictures.
Who's this? This is my father.
He's a teacher.
does he often do in his spare time?
He often goes fishing.
And is this your mother?
She looks beautiful.
Yeah, she likes reading.
She goes to the library three times a week.
I see. And this?
Oh, that's my brother.
He is an engineer.
Great. You have a happy family.
听下面一段对话。回答十四至十六小题。
Text 12 Hi, Tom.
I'm surprised to see you here.
Hi, Kate. I am so glad to see you.
So you like this place, too?
Of course. It's not very famous, but it has the most delicious Chinese food.
Yes. The waiter told me that the cook is one of the best in China.
Wow. The dishes here must be hard to cook.
That's right. Everyone needs to wait several minutes before they can enjoy their
food. It's 12.30 now.
I have been here for 30 minutes.
I'm so hungry.
Wait a moment.
It's your turn soon.
Text 12 Text 12 Text 13
听下面一段对话，回答十七至二十小题。
Hi, Paul. What a sunny day.
Yes, Maria. In fact, the good weather will last for a week.
Why not go out and do some outdoor activities?
Good idea. I hate watching movies at home every day.
Shall we go for a walk tomorrow?
Okay. Let's go to the Central Park.
It's very beautiful.
The Central Park is good, but there are so many people.
What about going to this city park?
Sounds great. The city park is big and new, and we can have lunch there.
Wonderful. We can also call Annie to join us.
She likes outdoor activities, too.
But Annie won't be free tomorrow.
Why? She told me that she has to prepare for the exam.
What a pity.
Hi, Paul. What a sunny day.
Yes, Maria. In fact, the good weather will last for a week.
Why not go out and do some outdoor activities?
Good idea. I hate watching movies at home every day.
Shall we go for a walk tomorrow?
Okay. Let's go to the Central Park.
It's very beautiful.
The Central Park is good, but there are so many people.
What about going to this city park?
Sounds great. The city park is big and new, and we can have lunch there.
Wonderful. We can also call Annie to join us.
She likes outdoor activities, too.
But Annie won't be free tomorrow.
Why? She told me that she has to prepare for the exam.
What a pity.
四短文理解。听下面一段短文，从每小题三个选项中选出相应问题的最佳选项。听短文前，你将有三十秒钟的时间阅读各小题。短文读两遍。
Thank you. Text 14
My name is Li Ping.
I am 15 years old.
I want to say something about Hero.
Maybe your Hero is a famous singer, a movie star, or a great man.
But my Hero is around me.
She is my mother, the real Hero in my heart.
She is a teacher.
She cares much about students' study and life, and she is always kind to them.
She also tells me to be kind to others.
When I was a baby, she taught me how to walk and how to speak.
When I do badly in study, she always encourages me.
On Mother's Day, I plan to write her a beautiful card and cook a meal for her.
I want to tell her how much I love and respect her.
My name is Li Ping.
I am 15 years old.
I want to say something about Hero.
Maybe your Hero is a famous singer, a movie star, or a great man.
But my Hero is around me.
She is my mother, the real Hero in my heart.
She is a teacher.
She cares much about students' study and life, and she is always kind to them.
She also tells me to be kind to others.
When I was a baby, she taught me how to walk and how to speak.
When I do badly in study, she always encourages me.
On Mother's Day, I plan to write her a beautiful card and cook a meal for her.
I want to tell her how much I love and respect her.
Thank you.